Mahmoud Zaky Fetoh

Phone: +201022381474 github.com/zaky-fetoh

Email: zaky.fetoh@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mahmoud-zaky-fetoh

Objective

I am a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in software engineering, passionate about solving real-world problems and collaborating with great engineers from whom I can learn.

I have diverse experience across various disciplines, including backend development, MLOps, computer vision research, and DevOps.

Work Experience

Dec 2023 - Present

ML Cloud Consultant @ Bexprt, UK.

Involved at architecting and implementing MLOps and DevOps projects for MENA customers.

- Job Role:
- Architecting scalable training and serving pipelines for ML models.
- o Managing AWS Cloud infrastructure across 7 AWS accounts for ML and Data teams.
- o Architecting cloud-native solutions and developing Infrastructure as Code (IaC) for them.
- o Designing solutions for large-scale data processing.
- Creating and executing large-scale migration plans.
- \circ Designing, developing, and maintaining scalable and reliable CI/CD pipelines.
- Managing and maintaining compute clusters in AWS (ECS and EKS).
- \circ Conducting rigorous comparisons of 3rd-party tools, selecting and integrating them into the infrastructure.
- Managing the monitoring solution and create tailored alerts.
- Continuously creating and updating documentation.
- Technologies:

Clould Provider: AWS, Cloudflare.

IaC: Terraform, SAM, Serverless-Framework.

CI/CD: Github Actions, Atlantis, Terraform Cloud.

ETL: AWS Glue Crawler, Glue Database, Glue Job, S3, Firehose.

MLOps: SageMaker, bentoml, Prefect, MLflow, DVC.

Micro-frontend: Cloudfront, S3, Route53. Container Orchestrators: ECS, EKS. Monitoring: DataDog, NewRelic.

May 2023 - Dec 2023

DevOps Engineer @ n-go, KSA.

Administrating the infrastucture for 1M user Application.

- Job Role:
- Administering and monitoring a microservices application with 1 million users running on a Kubernetes (Amazon EKS) cluster.
- \circ Administering and maintaining Jenkins CI pipelines for performing Dockerization and image scanning.
- Developing Infrastructure as Code (IaC) using Terraform, Kustomize, and Helm, ensuring all follow the GitOps pattern.
- Developing custom and secure automation solutions to increase developer productivity.
- Administering and maintaining GitOps CD pipelines for Kubernetes using ArgoCD.
- \circ Continuously enhancing the infrastructure and performing necessary migrations.
- \circ Writing and creating Prometheus dashboards using PromQL for Kubernetes.
- Ensuring security by implementing security best practices.
- \circ Administering RDS databases and MongoDB clusters.
- o Administering Cloudflare DNS and other services.
- Administering Twingate ZTN solutions.
- Technologies:

Clould Provider: AWS, OCI, Cloudflare. Container Orchestrators: EKS, OKE. CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub actions, ArgoCD.

kubernetes Autoscaler: Cluster Autoscaler, karpenter. Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, ELK, Kiali, Jaeger.

IaC: Terraform, Kustomize, Helm, Ansible.

VPN & ZTN: Pritunl, Twingate.

Service Mesh: Istio.

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

MLops Engineer @ Susoft, Norway.

Building microservice application for Training and deploying machine and deep learning models for Sales forecasting. Performing customer segmentation to direct marketing campaigns.

- Job Role:
- Creating a training and serving MLOps pipeline for multiple time series forecasting models, such as Prophet, Neural Prophet, and TFT.
- \circ Developing custom data pipelines for extracting, loading, and transforming required data from MariaDB databases.
- Evaluating and monitoring model performance.
- Ensuring high availability of the serving models.
- Technologies:

Model Training: PyTorchForecasting, Pytorch, pandas, Prophet, NeuralProphet.

Model Monitoring: Weight and biases, Prometheus, Grafana.

Model Serving: torchScript, Docker, K8s.

Model Registry: Minio.

Asynchronous communication for issuing train request is done using RabbitMQ Gateway and load balancing services performed using NodeJS.

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

Software Engineer @ Freelancer.

Bulding Microservices and monolithic applications.

- Job Role:
- Create complete RESTfull API, GraphQL Services following client requirements.
- Create documentation and Swagger documentation for it.
- o Building scalable and decupled architectures.
- Technologies:

Programming Languages: Python, NodeJS. HTTP Servers Frameworks: ExpressJS, Flask.

Authentication: Jsonwebtoken (JWT). Client API: REST, GraphQL, SocketIO.

Others: jest, Joi, Mongoose, amqp, sequelize, Crypto, axios, Multer, Docker-Compose.

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

Teaching & Research Assistant @ Menoufiya University, Egypt.

- Teaching courses on AI, deep learning, image processing, and computer vision.
- o Teaching the CCNA curriculum, preparing exams, and evaluating students.
- Teaching the MCSA curriculum, preparing exams, and evaluating students.
- \circ Teaching alorithms, data structure, Operating systems courses.
- o Teaching backend programming using Node.js.

Education

2021 - 2023

Faculty of Computers and Information, Menoufia university, Egypt.

M.Sc. in Computer Vision, specialized in deep learning research, graduated in 2023.

- Architected Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) for detecting COVID-19 in medical images.
- \circ Built training pipelines, validated model accuracy, and performed model comparison.
- o Monitored experiments, documented results, and writing papers.

2015 - 2019 | Faculty of Computers and Information, Menoufia university, Egypt.

B.Sc. Honors. I graduated with highest grade on my class with an Excellent honors GPA of 3.6.

• Hired as a Teaching Assistant at the same institute.

 \circ My graduation project created an intrusion detection system for detecting various network attacks in software-defined networks using deep learning CIC-IDS2017 is used a training dataset

Professional Certificates.

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate [Link] AWS Certified Machine Learning - Specialty [Link]

Frameworks & Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, NodeJS, GoLang (learning)

HTTP Servers Frameworks: ExpressJS, Flask.

Version Control Tools: Git. Github. Bitbucket.

Data Science: PyTorch, Pandas, statsmodels, Prophet, Numpy, OpenCV, Plotly,

LLAMA 2, PaddleOCR.

MLOps: SageMaker, Prefect, bentoml, Mlflow, Hydra, DVC.

Client API: REST, GraphQL, gRPC, SocketIO.

Security Utilities: Joi, Jsonwebtoken (JWT), OAuth 2.0.

MONGODE MySQL, PostgreSQL, M.

 ${\bf Databases:} \quad {\rm MONGODB, \, MySQL, \, PostgreSQL, \, MariaDB.}$

Adminstration: CCNA, MCSA, RHCSA, Kubernetes,

Clould Provider: AWS, OCI, Cloudflare.

Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, Loki, ELK, kiali, jaeger, DataDog, NewRelic.

Container Orchestrators: EKS, OKE, ECS, Docker-Compose.

Infrastucture as Code: Terraform, Kustomize, Helm, Ansible.

CI/CD: Atlantis, Terraform Cloud, Jenkins, Github Actions, ArgoCD.

VPN & ZTN: Pritunl, Twingate, Cloudflare Warp.

Message Broker: RabbitMQ, Kafka.

Documentation: Swagger, LaTeX.

Caching: Redis, MinIO.

Publications

2022 Multiscale aware classification of COVID-19 from Chest X-Ray using a spatially weighted atrous spatial pyramid pooling CNN [Link].

Mahmoud Z fetoh, Khalid M. Amin, Ahmed M. Hamad

In this paper I propose, scale invariant CNN architecture for COVID-19 classification. Proposed model based on building a scale space in each layer using Atrous spatial pyramid pooling then selecting a correct space to operate at using spatial attention module.

2021 COVID-19 Detection Based on Chest X-Ray Image Classification using Tailored CNN Model, [Link]. Mahmoud Z fetoh, Khalid M. Amin, Ahmed M. Hamad

In this paper I propose a very light-weight model as a consequence of using spatial separable kernel and depth-wise separable kernels for COVID-19 classification.

Published at: IJCI.